Christian Miko Tacdol

- CELL 09366912092 E-MAIL cmf.tacdol@gmail.com
- LOCATION Navotas City Metro Manila



PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Solution-driven professional excelling in a collaborative work environment, finding solutions to challenges and focused on customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused web sites using HTML, CSS, JQuery, PHP and JavaScript. Experience building products for desktop, phone and mobile app users, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices, usability and speed. Responding to challenges by designing and developing solutions and building web applications aligned to customer's services. Translating solutions into code and working across many different APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

SKILLS

•HTML & CSS

Video Editing

Flash Animation

JavaScript/jQuery

•3D Modeling

Payment API Integration

•PHP

MySQL

Bootstrap

Laravel

Photography

•Flutter

Firebase/Firestore

Photo Editing

CMS(Joomla, Wordpress)

Opencart

Videography

Google Cloud Platform

•P.O.S

•Git

•C#

Linux Server

Audio Editing

•SEO

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science Information Technology

Polytechnic University of the Philippines PUP A. Mabini Campus, Anona St. Sta. Mesa Manila, Philippines

WORK HISTORY

Multimedia & Website Developer

The WOW Group of Companies – 1081 EDSA Balintawak Quezon City (March 2014 –December 2016)

Website Developer

Fruitwishes International Co. – Unit 2301 World Trade Exchange Building Binondo Manila (January 2017 – September 2018)

Website Developer

JV. Angeles Construction Corp. #1 E. Rodriguez Jr. Avenue. Pasig City 1600 (October 2017 – November 2019)

Website Developer

Fruitwishes International Co. – Unit 2301 World Trade Exchange Building Binondo Manila (November 2019 – May 2020)

AINPEX SOLUTIONS CORP. –4L #222 Rizal Ave. Rojumar Building, Caloocan Manila (May 2020 – Present)

JOB EXPERIENCES

- Produce websites such as online stores using CMS or static and translate templates into web pages.
- Developed mobile apps using Flutter and Firebase.
- Developed websites using Firebase at it's database.

•

- Design websites and ensure that they are visually effective, responsive user interface for web and mobile devices and easy to access, ensuring strong functionality and optimization.
- Identify and eliminate website bugs to improve user experience.
- Maximized user flow in the retail section of the website, resulting in an increase in completed purchases.
- Create, develop and conceptualize website plug-in to meet the requirements of the clients.
- In house photographer and videographer.
- Creates animations for websites and other media.
- Creates, Edits and Conceptualize video presentations.
- Maximizes the usage of Google web tools.
- Maximizes the usage of Google Analytics.
- Assists analysis in both Facebook pages and website pages.
- Create and deploy a website with Google Cloud Platform

- Reverse engineer an existing website to know the ins and outs then proceed with the tasks given.
- Conceptualize, Analyze, Documented and Developed using c# to make a Point of Sales application for a cash register.
- Developed RESTful Web APIs using Laravel
- Normalizing databases
- Collaborated with mobile developers for API usage and integration to their mobile applications for an inventory system.
- Developed e-commerce sites.

TRAININGS

- August 28, 2012 | First IT Research Forum. Bulwagang Balagtas PUP-NALLRC
- August 24, 2013 | iSHARE: On the Hot Seat Interview Portion Tips and Tricks to Nail the Job Interview. Bulwagang Balagtas PUP-NALLRC.
- December 3, 2011 | Microsoft Academic Team Philippines, Microsoft Student Partners. Microsoft Web Matrix and Windows 8 Consumer preview. Bulwagang Balagtas, PUP-NALLRC.
- March 20,2012 | Academic Seminar entitled "A look Outside the Windows: Ubuntu and Linux Operating System". PUP-Main Campus, S604 South Wing.
- October 17 21 2012 | Technical Documentation and Presentation Skills and Web-Based Programming. 9th TechDoc&WebProg Coursework Summit held at Teachers Camp, Baguio City, Philippines.
- Cyber Safety & data Privacy Compliance Forum April 11, 2019 8:30 AM to 5:30 PM AIM CONFERENCE CENTER Benavidez corner Trasierra Streets, Legaspi Village, Makati City, Philippines